Hello everyone and welcome
to English Pot Happy New Year.
My name is Marco and I'm Erica.
Happy New Year. Happy New Year Marco.
It's December 31st and we are
on New Year's Eve. That's right and
since it's New Year's Eve, we're
talking about New Year's resolutions.
Right, in many places it's very
common to make a promise
for the New Year, something
that you will change.
A promise to
yourself. To yourself.
To change something. And that's
what our dialogue is about today.
So why don't we take a look at a
vocabulary preview for this lesson?
Very cablery preview.
Okay, on vocabulary preview
today we only have one word.
Eating habits. Eating habits.
Eating habits. So what are eating habits?
The regular way you
eat. Right. So if you eat
healthy or if you eat
lots of unhealthy food,
or even maybe what time you eat,
right, if you eat every day a certain time?
Yeah. Eating habits. Okay.
So we're ready to listen to
our dialogue today and it's going to be
a little bit fast but don't worry about it.
We'll come back and explain
all of the key vocabulary after.
So did I tell you about my New Year's
resolution? I've decided to go on a diet.
And you're going to completely
transform your eating habits, right?
Exactly. I'm going to
cut out all the junk I eat.
No more chips, no more
soda, no more fried food.
Uh-huh. I've heard this one before.
But this time I'm going to stick to it.
I really mean it. Trust me Carol,
I'm going to be a new
man in one year's time.
Well, I guess we'll just
have to wait and see.
Thanks honey.
That was a great meal. I'm stuffed.
Do we have any chips left?
So Marco, do you think this guy will be
successful in changing his eating habits?
Well, I guess he'll never
change but this gives
us a great opportunity
to look at some great
vocabulary in this lesson
in language takeaway.
Language takeaway. Our first word on
language takeaway is junk, junk, junk, junk.
So junk comes from junk food.
Exactly. Unhealthy food. Yeah.
Fries, chips, hamburgers. Yeah.
All that junk. All that junk.
Okay. Our second word for
language takeaway transform.
Transform. Transform.
Meaning to change.
Yep. Change. So this guy is
going to transform his eating habits.
He's going to change
his eating habits. Yeah.
Our third word is
stuffed, stuffed, stuffed.
I'm stuffed. So we have
some great examples
on how we can use stuffed and you'll
get the meaning from it. Example one.
Come on. I have one more piece of cake.
Oh, I can't. I'm stuffed.
Okay. I'm stuffed.
The feeling you get if
you eat too much
food. Right. I'm full. Yeah.
All right. So these are
some great words that
you can use talking about
food and eating habits.
And now we can listen to
our dialogue a second time
and this time, like always,
it's going to be slow.
So did I tell you about
my new year's resolution?
I've decided to go on a
diet and you're going to
completely transform
your eating habits, right?
Exactly. I'm going to
cut out all that junk I eat.
No more chips. No more soda. No more fried
food. Uh-huh. I've heard this one before.
But this time I'm
going to stick to it.
I really mean it. Trust
me, Carol. I'm going to
be a new man in one year's time. Well,
I guess we'll just have to wait and see.
Thanks, honey. That was a great meal.
I'm stuffed. Do we have any chips left?
There's a lot of great language
in the dialogue isn't there.
Yeah, a lot of great language that we can
take a look at with our fluency builder.
Fluency builder. The
first phrase we have
for you is, stick to it.
Stick to it. Stick to it.
Yes. We've got some examples
of how this phrase is used.
So let's listen. Example one.
Quitting smoking is so hard.
Stick to it. It's good for you.
Example two.
I can't solve this math problem.
Stick to it. I'm sure you'll get it.
So stick to it, right?
Basically means keep doing
it. Right. Even though
English learning can be hard,
you should stick
to it. Yeah. Exactly.
Okay, let's look at our second
phrase for fluency builder.
I mean it. Mean it. Oh,
this is a great way of saying.
I'm serious. I'm
serious. Yeah. I mean it.
I'm not joking. I'm not joking. Yeah.
And our final phrase in fluency builder.
Cut out. Cut out. Cut
out. Again, we've got some
examples of this phrase
as native speakers use it.
Let's listen. Example one.
You have to cut out
the salt from your diet.
No more chips. No more
french fries. No more popcorn.
Example two.
It's time for me to
focus on my work.
I'm going to cut out
everything else from my life.
Okay, so cut out means to remove completely
removed. Take it away. Take it away. Yeah.
Okay, some great language,
some great phrases in
our dialogue today. So
why don't we listen to it
a third time and we'll
come back in a little bit.
So did I tell you about
my New Year's resolution?
I've decided to go on a
diet and you're going to
completely transform
your eating habits, right?
Exactly. I'm going to
cut out all the junk I eat.
No more chips. No more soda. No more fried
food. Uh-huh. I've heard this one before.
But this time I'm going to stick to it.
I really mean it. Trust me, Carol,
I'm going to be a new
man in one year's time.
Well, I guess we'll just
have to wait and see.
Thanks, honey.
That was a great meal. I'm stuffed.
Do we have any chips left?
Okay, so New Year's resolutions are really
common and popular thing in North America.
It's tradition to make a promise
to yourself on New Year's
and stick to it throughout
the whole year. Right.
But the funny thing
is that very few people
actually stick to their
New Year's resolution.
That's true. The most common
ones are I'm going to quit smoking.
Yeah. That never happens. No.
I'm going to go on a diet like
this guy. I'm going to quit drinking.
Uh-huh. That almost never
happens either on New Year's Eve.
I mean, it's a bad
time. Come on.
And another really common
one is I'm going to join a gym.
That's why gym membership
sales are so high in January.
Right. Everyone
joins a gym in January,
but kind of February and very
few people in the gym. Yeah.
So Marco, do you have a New
Year's resolution for this year?
Yes. I have a New
Year's resolution and I
resolve to continue bringing
everyone some great lessons.
Oh, that's that's so good. And
I think I can stick to that one.
Yes. Well, I do hope that you
do stick to that one, Marco.
We will, we will. But
today we're out of time.
So please go to our
website and leave all your
questions and comments
at EnglishPod.com.
And we'll see you there.
But until then, it's goodbye.